Becca King

TITLE

Full-Stack Web Developer with Journalism Experience

CONTACT

216-570-0627 rebecca.lynne.king@gmail.com Cleveland, OH 44102

WEBSITE

rebeccaking.info

SKILLS

JavaScript
JavaScript libraries (jQuery,
Parsley, React)
CSS
CSS preprocessors (Less)
HTML5
Progress OpenEdge
Microsoft SQL Server

EDUCATION

General Assembly
Software Engineering
Certificate program in
full-stack web development.
Created web applications using
JavaScript, jQuery, PHP,
Angular, React, SQL, MongoDb,
HTML, CSS, Git version control.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with a background in journalism, and I am passionate about creating engaging online experiences for diverse audiences. I've worked closely with news editors, information technologists, designers, and e-commerce experts.

EXPERIENCE

Amerimark Direct, LLC, Web Developer

Middleburg Heights, OH - Nov 2020 - Current

- Primary front-end specialist on a team of web developers.
- Developed front and back end solutions based on design specifications and information technology needs.
- Completed training in React, SQL, and web accessibility.

North Coast Media, Web Developer

Cleveland, OH - Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Full stack development of websites based on a WordPress
- Technologies used include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, WordPress, PHP, SQL, Google Tag Manager.
- Developed websites to work properly across multiple browsers, including those created by Microsoft, Google, and Mozilla.

Becca King, LLC, Freelance Writer

Jul 2020 - Current

- Wrote magazine articles for *Teen Vogue* and *LGBTQ Nation*.
- Researched and reported original news stories for The Athens News and The Athens Messenger.
- Worked as a ghostwriter for We Write Blog Posts, later promoted to an editing position.

Ohio University, Graduate Assistant in Journalism

Miami University
Bachelor of Science
Kinesiology
Environmental Science
University Honors Program

E.W. Scripps School of
Journalism, Ohio University
Master of Science
Journalism
Athens, Ohio
Completed two years of
coursework in digital media,
communication law, and media
economics before leaving out
of medical necessity.

Athens, OH - Aug 2017 - May 2019

- Studied the fundamentals of digital journalism, communication law, and media economics to become a well-rounded professional in the journalism field.
- Worked as a research assistant in journalism for varied university departments.

Americorps - La Puente Shelter, Community Educator and Volunteer Coordinator

Alamosa, CO - Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- Created news and radio press releases on behalf of a rural homeless shelter.
- Built relationships with the local community and visiting volunteers.
- Gathered and edited stories for and designed a 32-page storybook on behalf of the organization. Used Indesign and Adobe Photoshop under the guidance of a professional graphic designer.